A Guide to the American Society of International Law records, Howard M. Holtzmann papers FA1872
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Organizations, 1957-2010; VII; 7.06 Cubic Feet 15 legal document boxes
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Meeting Minutes - General, 1988-1996 (Box 127, Folder 3-5, Box 128, Folder 1-2)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Meeting Minutes - Warsaw, Poland, 1980 (Box 128, Folder 3)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Meeting Minutes - Paris, 1997 (Box 128, Folder 4)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Meeting Minutes - Stockholm, 1995 March (Box 128, Folder 5)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Meeting Minutes - Vienna, 1994 (Box 128, Folder 6)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Meeting Minutes - Paris, 1994 (Box 128, Folder 7)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Meeting Minutes - Seoul, 1996 (Box 128, Folder 8)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Meeting Minutes - Council, 1996 (Box 128, Folder 9)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Papers, 2001-2004 (Box 128, Folder 10, Box 129, Folder 1)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Restructuring - Associates, 1993 (Box 129, Folder 1A)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Restructuring - Bahrain Discussion, 1993 (Box 129, Folder 2)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Restructuring - Comments on Drafts, 1993 (Box 129, Folder 3-4)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Restructuring - Constitutional Committee, 1989 (Box 129, Folder 5)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Restructuring - Documents, 1992 (Box 129, Folder 6)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Restructuring - Drafts, 1993 (Box 129, Folder 7)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Restructuring - General, 1989 (Box 129, Folder 8)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Restructuring - Guidelines, Draft, 1993 (Box 129, Folder 9)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Restructuring - Reports, 1993 (Box 129, Folder 10)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Restructuring - Revision of Statement of Purpose and Procedures, 1993-1994 (Box 129, Folder 11)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Restructuring - Statement of Purpose and Procedures, 1993 (Box 129, Folder 12)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Website, 2008-2009 (Box 129, Folder 13)
  - International Council for Commercial Arbitration - Correspondence, 2007-2010 (Box 129, Folder 14, Box 130, Folder 1)
  - International Centre for the Settlement of Investment Disputes, 1995-2001 (Box 130, Folder 2)
  - International Court of Justice, 2008 (Box 130, Folder 3)
  - International Arbitration Committee, 1980-1985 (Box 130, Folder 4)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - Administrative Council Meeting Minutes, 2009 (Box 130, Folder 5)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - Ameli Proposals on Annulment and Revisions, 1999 (Box 130, Folder 6)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - Basic Documents - Extra Copies, 1957-1996 (Box 130, Folder 7-8, Box 131, Folder 1-3)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - Correspondence and Memos, 1995-1996 (Box 131, Folder 4)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - Fact Finding Procedures - Drafts, 1996-1997 (Box 131, Folder 5)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - Introduction, 1995 (Box 131, Folder 6)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - Jonkman, Hans, 1993 (Box 131, Folder 7)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - Meeting, 1995 January (Box 131, Folder 8)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - Mass Claims Project, 2000 (Box 132, Folder 1)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - PCA-ICDR Meeting, Brussels, 2003 (Box 132, Folder 2)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - South Africa, 2002-2009 (Box 132, Folder 3)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - Steering Committee, 1999 (Box 132, Folder 4-5)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - Tjaco, T. van den Hout, 2002 (Box 132, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Department of State Advisory Committee on Private International Law, 1979 (Box 132, Folder 7)
  - World Intellectual Property Organization, 1979 (Box 132, Folder 8)
- Claims Resolution Tribunal (CRT), 1997-2002; VIII; 1.88 Cubic Feet 4 legal document boxes
  From 1997-2001, Judge Holtzmann worked as an arbitrator on the Claims Resolution Tribunal I and II. This series contains material produced as a consequence of that work, including correspondence, reference and research material, writings and drafts of rules and resolutions, and organizational and administrative records.
  - CRT I - General, 1998-2002 (Box 133, Folder 1-4)
  - CRT I - Applicable Law Guidelines, 1999-2000 (Box 133, Folder 5)
  - CRT I - ASA Conference, 1999 (Box 133, Folder 6)
  - CRT I - Expenses, 1999-2000 (Box 134, Folder 1-2)
  - CRT I - Historic Materials, 1998-1999 (Box 134, Folder 3)
  - CRT I - HMH Appointment Disclosures, 1997-1999 (Box 134, Folder 4)
  - CRT I - HMH Comments on Procedures, 1998-1999 (Box 134, Folder 5)
  - CRT I - Interest and Fees - Development of Guidelines, 1999 (Box 134, Folder 6)
  - CRT I - Interest and Fees - Final Rules, 2000 (Box 134, Folder 7)
  - CRT I - National Fonds, 2001 (Box 134, Folder 8)
  - CRT I - Rules of Procedure for the Claims Resolution Process, 1997 (Box 134, Folder 9)
  - CRT I - Press Clippings, 1997 April-1999 December (Box 134, Folder 10, Box 135, Folder 1-4)
  - CRT I - Press Packs, 2000-2001 (Box 135, Folder 5, Box 136, Folder 1)
  - CRT I - Settlement-Liability and Insurance-Interest and Fees, 1998-1999 (Box 136, Folder 2)
  - CRT I - Volcker Report, 1999 (Box 136, Folder 3)
  - CRT II - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 136, Folder 4)
  - CRT II - Reference Material, 2001 (Box 136, Folder 5)
  - CRT II - Special Master's Proposal, 2000 (Box 136, Folder 6)
- Business Files, 1973-2013; IX; 5.18 Cubic Feet 11 legal document boxes
  This series is comprised of the business chronological files of Judge Holtzmann.
  The records provide information unique to this series, as well as cross-reference material on similar subjects found elswhere in the collection.
  Arranged alphabetically, in original order, as received. Primarily arranged by organization, institution, particular project, broad themes and subjects, and persons of interest to the various legal and arbitration work of Holtzmann.
  - American Association for the International Commission of Jurists, 1995-2007 (Box 137, Folder 1)
  - American Judicature Society, 1995-2013 (Box 137, Folder 2)
  - American Society of International Law, 1973-2007 (Box 137, Folder 3-5)
  - American Society of International Law - Honorary Member, 1995-2005 (Box 137, Folder 6)
  - American Arbitration Association - General, 1984-2013 (Box 137, Folder 7-9, Box 138, Folder 1-2)
  - American Arbitration Association - 75th Anniversary, 1999 (Box 138, Folder 3)
  - American Arbitration Association - Martinez, Louis, 1997 (Box 138, Folder 4)
  - American Arbitration Association - Arbitration Committee, 1996-2002 (Box 138, Folder 5)
  - American Arbitration Association - Bylaws, 2002 (Box 138, Folder 6)
  - American Arbitration Association - Meetings, 1992-2004 (Box 138, Folder 7-9, Box 139, Folder 1-4)
  - American Arbitration Association - Task Force, 2007-2008 (Box 139, Folder 5)
  - ABILA - Memberships, 2008-2009 (Box 139, Folder 6)
  - American Bar Association, 1985-2012 (Box 139, Folder 7)
  - ADR Associates, 1996 (Box 139, Folder 8)
  - American Foreign Law, 1983-2006 (Box 139, Folder 9)
  - Appellate Division Committee on C and F, 1995 (Box 139, Folder 10)
  - Arbitration Institute of Stockholm, 1994 (Box 139, Folder 11)
  - Arbitration Activities, 1992 (Box 139, Folder 12)
  - Arbitration International - Publication of HMH Freshfield Lecture and Faxes, 1995 (Box 139, Folder 13)
  - Arbitration - Russian, 2005-2007 (Box 139, Folder 14)
  - ASA, 1998 (Box 140, Folder 1)
  - Asser Institute - 70s, 80s, 90s, and Onward, 1995-2002 (Box 140, Folder 2)
  - Asser Institute - The Hague 75th Anniversary, 1998 (Box 140, Folder 3)
  - Asser Institute - Evaluation Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 140, Folder 4)
  - Association of the Bar of the City of New York, 1985-2001 (Box 140, Folder 5)
  - Australian Center for International Arbitration, 1997 (Box 140, Folder 6)
  - Boalt Hall Law School, 1995 (Box 140, Folder 7)
  - Baker and McKenzie, 1997 (Box 140, Folder 8)
  - Center for American and International Business, 2006-2011 (Box 140, Folder 9)
  - The Chartered Institute of Arbitrators, 1995-1999 (Box 140, Folder 10)
  - CIETAC, 2001 (Box 140, Folder 11)
  - CLE - Credits, 2006 (Box 140, Folder 12)
  - Club of Arbitrators, 1998-1999 (Box 140, Folder 13)
  - Code of Ethics, 2001 (Box 140, Folder 14)
  - College of Commercial Arbitrators, 2001-2010 (Box 140, Folder 15)
  - Commercial Law Association, 1997-1998 (Box 140, Folder 16)
  - Environmental Law Institute - General, 1999-2013 (Box 141, Folder 1)
  - Environmental Law Institute - Carothers, 2003-2005 (Box 141, Folder 1A)
  - Essex Court Chambers, 1996 (Box 141, Folder 2)
  - Euromoney, 1996 (Box 141, Folder 3)
  - Freshfields, 1995-1998 (Box 141, Folder 4)
  - Friends of the Hague - Academy of International Law, 1996-1998 (Box 141, Folder 5)
  - Friends of the Hague - General, 1996 (Box 141, Folder 6)
  - Hague Conference on Private International Law, 1998 (Box 141, Folder 7)
  - Hague - Miscellaneous, 1991-2000 (Box 141, Folder 8)
  - HMH State Department, 2003 (Box 141, Folder 9)
  - Human Rights First, 2004 (Box 141, Folder 10)
  - IACAC - Rules, 1997-2000 (Box 141, Folder 11)
  - ICAC - Membership, 2005 (Box 141, Folder 12)
  - ICC - General, 2001 (Box 141, Folder 13)
  - ICC, 1997-2002 (Box 141, Folder 14-17)
  - ICCA - General, 2000-2012 (Box 142, Folder 1)
  - ICCA - London Conference, 2002 (Box 142, Folder 2)
  - ICCA - 90s, 1997-1999 (Box 142, Folder 3)
  - ICCA - Paris, 1996 (Box 142, Folder 4)
  - ICCA, 1989-1991 (Box 142, Folder 5)
  - ICCA - The Hague, 1998 December (Box 142, Folder 6)
  - ICCA - Handbook, 1998-2011 (Box 142, Folder 7)
  - ICSID, 2000 (Box 142, Folder 8)
  - ILSA, 1999 (Box 142, Folder 9)
  - ILA, 1978-1999 (Box 142, Folder 10-12)
  - Institute of International Commercial Law - Moot Court, 1994 (Box 142, Folder 13)
  - International Arbitration Committee, 1995 (Box 142, Folder 14)
  - International Association of Jewish Lawyers, 2010 (Box 142, Folder 15)
  - International Bar Association, 1996-2010 (Box 142, Folder 16)
  - International Law Week, 1998-1999 (Box 143, Folder 1)
  - International Society for Labor Law, 1996 (Box 143, Folder 2)
  - Iran-US Claims Tribunal - General, 2001-2011 (Box 143, Folder 3)
  - Iran-US Claims Tribunal - Challenge of Judge Broms, 2001 (Box 143, Folder 4)
  - Iran-US Claims Tribunal, 1990-1998 (Box 143, Folder 5-7)
  - International Institute for the Unification of Private Law, 1998 (Box 143, Folder 8)
  - Law Business Research, 2001 (Box 143, Folder 9)
  - Law Clerks, 2007-2010 (Box 143, Folder 10)
  - Law Library, 2008 (Box 143, Folder 11)
  - LCIA - Membership, 1995-2008 (Box 144, Folder 1)
  - LCIA - North American Council - Bermuda, 1996 (Box 144, Folder 2)
  - Malta Arbitration Centre, 2004 (Box 144, Folder 3)
  - Mass Claims Book Related, 2006-2007 (Box 144, Folder 4)
  - Mauritius, 1996 (Box 144, Folder 5)
  - Membership Lists, 2007 (Box 144, Folder 6)
  - Memberships - New York City Bar Association, 2011 (Box 144, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 2008-2012 (Box 144, Folder 8)
  - NAFTA, 1994-1995 (Box 144, Folder 9)
  - New York City Bar Association, 2013 (Box 144, Folder 10)
  - New York County Lawyers, 1992-2012 (Box 144, Folder 11)
  - New York State Bar Association, 1996-2013 (Box 144, Folder 12)
  - NVIK/ASIL, 1997 (Box 144, Folder 13)
  - State of New York - Office of Court Administration, 1979-2001 (Box 144, Folder 14)
  - Office of the Legal Advisor, 1996-1997 (Box 144, Folder 15)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - Miscellaneous, 2002-2009 (Box 144, Folder 16)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - 1999, 1998-2010 (Box 144, Folder 17)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - Mass Claims Steering Committee, 2001 (Box 144, Folder 18)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - Request for Assistance, 2012 (Box 145, Folder 1)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - Bosnia, 1996-1999 (Box 145, Folder 2)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration - The Hague, 1995-1999 (Box 145, Folder 3)
  - National Center for State Courts, 1995 (Box 145, Folder 4)
  - Society of Professionals in Dispute Resolution, 1976-1995 (Box 145, Folder 5)
  - Southwestern Legal Foundation, 1995-1996 (Box 145, Folder 6)
  - Transnational, 1998-2001 (Box 145, Folder 7)
  - Telders International Law Moot Court, 1995-1997 (Box 145, Folder 8)
  - Jessup Moot Court Competition, 1997 (Box 145, Folder 9)
  - UNCITRAL - NY Convention, 1998 (Box 145, Folder 10)
  - UNCITRAL - 25th Anniversary Party, 1992 (Box 145, Folder 11)
  - UNCITRAL - General, 1983-2010 (Box 145, Folder 12-13)
  - UNTAD - Handbook, 2002 (Box 146, Folder 1)
  - UNIDROIT, 1995-1999 (Box 146, Folder 2)
  - Uniform Law, 2003 (Box 146, Folder 3)
  - UN Information, 2008 (Box 146, Folder 4)
  - Private International Law, 1979-1989 (Box 146, Folder 5)
  - Review of Guide of the UNCTIRAL Model, 1978-1997 (Box 146, Folder 6)
  - World Intellectual Property Organization, 1997 (Box 146, Folder 7)
  - Speeches - Recent Articles and Speeches, undated (Box 146, Folder 8)
  - Speeches - NYU, 2002 (Box 146, Folder 9)
  - Speeches - The Hague, 1999 May 17-19 (Box 146, Folder 10)
  - Speeches - Berkeley, 1999 (Box 147, Folder 1)
  - Speeches - Zurich, 1999 January (Box 147, Folder 2)
  - Speeches - NY - International Law Weekend, 1998 November (Box 147, Folder 3)
  - Speeches - The Hague, 1997-1998 (Box 147, Folder 4-5)
  - Speeches - Boston, 1997 February 4 (Box 147, Folder 6)
  - Speeches, 1996 November 25 (Box 147, Folder 7)
  - Speeches - New York, 1996 November 15 (Box 147, Folder 8)
  - Speeches - Venezuela, 1996 November 8 (Box 147, Folder 9)
  - Speeches - Boston, 1996 September-October (Box 147, Folder 10-12)
  - Speeches, 1994 June and 1996 June (Box 147, Folder 13-14)
  - Speeches - London, 1993 September 22 (Box 147, Folder 15)
  - Yale Dedication of Portrait, 2007 (Box 147, Folder 16)
- Personal, 1941-2012; X; 8.01 Cubic Feet 17 legal document boxes
  This series contains items related to Judge Holtzmann in a personal capacity, including financial documents, notes, and materials relating to his family. Many documents, including correspondence and financial material, pertaining to Holtzmann's longstanding involvement in the governance, academics, and endowment of Yale and the Yale Law School are contained here. Additionally, this series contains correspondence and records related to Holtzmann's work at the law firm of Holtzmann, Wise, and Sheppard. This series also contains the printed and published material used and retained by Holtzmann for reference and research. Materials include journals, pamphlets, books and periodicals.
  - General, 1996-2005 (Box 147, Folder 17)
  - Address Lists, 1992-1993 (Box 147, Folder 18)
  - Appointment Calendars, 2000-2012 (Box 148, Folder 1-2)
  - Navy, 1942 (Box 148, Folder 3)
  - Bill of Sale - Purchase Agreement, 1963 (Box 148, Folder 4)
  - Calendar, 2012 (Box 148, Folder 5)
  - Caneel, 2004 (Box 148, Folder 6)
  - Certificate, undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Citations for Awards, Medals, and Prizes, 2012 (Box 148, Folder 7)
    Listed Chronologically
  - Finances - College of Commercial Arbitrators, 2006 (Box 148, Folder 8)
  - Finances - Invoices - Miscellaneous, 1992-1994 (Box 148, Folder 9)
  - Finances - NY Weill/Cornell Medical Center Council, 2006 (Box 148, Folder 10)
  - Frakenslag Break-In (Box 148, Folder 11)
  - George H. W. Bush Inaugural Reception, 1981 (Box 148, Folder 12)
  - Hague Memorabilia, undated (Box 148, Folder 13)
  - Henry Holtzmann, 1941 (Box 148, Folder 14)
  - HMH 65th Birthday Party, 1986 (Box 148, Folder 15)
  - HMH Illness, 1993 (Box 148, Folder 16)
    Progress Report and messages
  - Holtzmann, Wise, and Sheppard - Correspondence and Memos, 1996-1997 (Box 148, Folder 17)
  - Holtzmann, Wise, and Sheppard Files, undated (Box 148, Folder 18)
  - Holtzmann, Wise, and Sheppard - HMH and Rosen Memos and Syntex Fees and Exxon Valdez, 1995 (Box 148, Folder 19)
  - Holtzmann, Wise, and Sheppard - HMH Liability on Bank Loans, 1993-1995 (Box 148, Folder 20)
  - Holtzmann, Wise, and Sheppard - HMH Liability on Lease, 1993 (Box 149, Folder 1)
  - Holtzmann, Wise, and Sheppard - HMH Materials in Safe, 1995 (Box 149, Folder 2)
  - Holtzmann, Wise, and Sheppard - Withdrawing as Partner and Removing Name, 1993-1995 (Box 149, Folder 3)
  - Holtzmann, Wise, and Sheppard - Office, 1986-1995 (Box 149, Folder 4)
  - Holtzmann, Wise, and Sheppard - Partnership Agreement, 1986 (Box 149, Folder 5)
  - Holtzmann, Wise, and Sheppard - Removal of Paneling on HMH Office, 1995 (Box 149, Folder 6)
  - Holtzmann, Wise, and Sheppard - Resignation Announcement, undated (Box 149, Folder 7)
  - Holtzmann, Wise, and Sheppard - US Trust, 1991-1996 (Box 149, Folder 8)
  - Jacob Holtzmann Last Will and Testament, 1963 (Box 149, Folder 9)
  - JTS Honorary Degrees Committee Meeting, 2012 (Box 149, Folder 10)
  - Judiac Services, undated (Box 149, Folder 11)
  - Lawyers Weekly Report, 1954 (Box 149, Folder 12)
  - Mamaroneck, 1981 (Box 149, Folder 13)
  - Notes, undated (Box 149, Folder 14)
  - Photographs - General, 1980s-2000s (Box 149, Folder 15)
  - Photographs - Budapest Funeral of Rabbi Sheider, 1988 (Box 149, Folder 16)
  - Photographs - Henry and Theresa Holtzmann, 1992-2000s (Box 149, Folder 17)
  - Polar Star Award - Certificate, 2004 (Box 149, Folder 18)
  - Polar Star Award - Medal, 2004 (Box 149, Folder 19)
  - Receptions, 1988-1989 (Box 150, Folder 1)
  - Printed Material - General, 1955-2011 (Box 150, Folder 2-4, Box 151, Folder 1-4)
  - Printed Material - General, 1955-2011 (Box 152, Folder 1-4, Box 153)
  - Printed Material - General, 1955-2011 (Box 154, Folder 1-4, Box 155)
  - Printed Material - General, 1955-2011 (Box 156, Folder 1-3, Box 157)
  - Printed Material - General, 1955-2011 (Box 158, Folder 1-4, Box 159)
  - Printed Material - Alabama Claims, 1885 (Box 160, Folder 1)
  - Printed Material - Brochures of Programs on which Howard H. Holtzmann has Lectured, 1971-1980 (Box 160, Folder 2)
  - Printed Material - Report of the Lemmon Slave Case, 1886 (Box 160, Folder 3)
  - Printed Material - The Relevance of the Experience of the Iran-United States Claims Tribunal, 1999 (Box 160, Folder 4)
  - Printed Material - International Arbitration Materials, 1980-2010 (Box 160, Folder 5-6, Box 161, Folder 1)
  - Yale - Alumni Fund - Class of '42 - General, 2004-2006 (Box 161, Folder 2-4)
  - Yale - Alumni Fund - Class of '42 - 50th Reunion, 1989-1992 (Box 162, Folder 1)
  - Yale - Alumni Fund - Class of '42 - Correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box 162, Folder 2)
  - Yale - Correspondence, 2002-2007 (Box 162, Folder 3)
  - Yale - Endowments - General, 1992-1997 (Box 162, Folder 4)
  - Yale - Endowments - Howard M. Holtzmann Fund for International Programs at Yale Law School, 1992-2004 (Box 162, Folder 5)
  - Yale - Endowments - Howard M. Holtzmann Professorship of International Law at Yale Law School, 1997 (Box 162, Folder 6)
  - Yale - Endowments - Joseph Slifka Center for Jewish Life at Yale - Board of Trustees Meeting, 1964-2001 (Box 162, Folder 7)
  - Yale - Endowments - Judaic Studies Fellowship, 1984 (Box 162, Folder 8)
  - Yale - Photographs, undated (Box 162, Folder 9)
  - Yale - To Do, 2005 (Box 162, Folder 10)